斯坦福大学
> Stanford University.
欢迎来到CS193P课程 2013-14秋季第17讲
> Alright, well welcome to lecture 17 of CS193P, Fall 2013/14.
今天我将先花几分钟时间
And today I'm going to spend just a couple minutes typing
对周一的demo进行一些查漏补缺
up some loose ends from the demo we had on Monday,
然后再来讨论摄像头拍照
and then I'm going to talk about taking pictures with the camera.
然后这方面也有一个demo
And then we'll do a demo about that.
继续用Photomania 继续上次的demo来
And that's basically PhotoMania, what we kind of set this all up for in our last demo.
然后我们会谈到Core Motion
Then we'll talk about core motion,
也就是加速计 陀螺仪这些东西
which is the accelerometer and the gyro and all that business,
然后我会演示这个
and I'll have a demo of that.
最后如果时间允许
And if time permitting at the end here,
我们还会简要讨论应用程序生命周期
we'll talk a little bit about the application life cycle.
我们讨论过视图控制器生命周期
We talked about the view controller life cycle
它什么时候出现 什么时候消失 等等
where it appears and disappears and all those things,
应用程序也有生命周期
well the application kind of, you know,
你到前台 你运行 然后你消失
you come into the foreground, you run, then you go away,
你到后台 然后回来 这里也有生命周期
then you go the background, you come back, so there's kind of a life cycle there too,
我们可以简要谈下这个
which we can talk about briefly,
有时间的话 这个我也可以演示一下
and I could even demo some of that if we have time.
先来看看上次的demo
Alright, so let's talk about the demo.
我要快速看看这个demo 并讲两点
I'm going to go back to the demo here real quick and talk about two things.
一是清理imageURL
One was cleaning up image URLs
因为对于imageURL 我们有这个getter
because the way we do our URLs is we have this "getter" for image URL,
只要有人想要图像视图中图像的URL
and any time someone wants a URL for the image that's in our image view,
我们就会创建一个文件到磁盘上 并返回URL
why we just create a file on disc and return the URL.
这是请求式的
So it's kind of on-demand.
问题在于 如果拍了另外一张照片
Well, the problem is, what if they then take a different photo
或者如果视图控制器离开屏幕然后回到屏幕
or if this view controller goes off screen and back on screen,
有人选了别的什么
and someone picked something else,
你不希望原来的URL还在那里
you don't want any old URLs lying around.
我们需要清理那些老旧的URL
So we need to clean up those old URLs.
另外我还要简单讲一点
And the other thing I'm going to show you, just a brief bit more
关于在Core Location检查错误
about checking for errors in core location.
我们已经做了一些错误检查
Because we did some error checking already,
不过我们还可以做更多一些
but we could do just slightly a bit more.
让我们回到Photomania
So let's go back to PhotoMania.
看看这个
And let's look at that.
imageURL的清理其实有两件事
The cleaning up the image stuff is really two things.
一是在取消时
One, when we cancel.
当我们取消 从模态视图控制器中退出时
When we do our cancel to get out of our modal view controller,
我们会将图像设为nil 为什么要这样做呢
we're going to set our image to nil, and why are we going to do that?
原因是这样 你可以看我们的设置图像方法 下面这里
That's because if you look at our set image, down here,
我们会删除URL
we delete the URLs, right?
只要图像视图中的图像改变了
So whenever we change the image that's in our image view, right?
我们就会删除URL
We delete the URLs. This is something we did,
上次课最后可能做得有些匆忙
kind of it was a little rushed maybe at the end,
不过我们的确删除了URL
but we do delete our URLs there.
这是因为我们有了新图像
And that's because we've got a new image, so we're going
我们于是想删掉旧图像的URL
to delete the URLs for the old image, and that will make,
这就将URL设为nil 我们会创建新URL
we'll set our URL to nil, so that we'll make new URLs, right?
这就是我们要清理的地方
So this is where we're going to clean up.
在取消时 我们显然需要把图像设为nil
So we definitely want to set that image to nil when we cancel.
另一点是 不取消时
And the other thing is, when we don't cancel,
如果我们要实际准备segue并创建照片
when we actually prepare for segue and make a photo,
那我们就希望将URL设为nil 让它们不被删除
then we want to set the URLs to nil, so that they don't get deleted.
因为这里 我们在照片中将URL汇报回去
Because here, we're reporting that URL back in the photo,
我们不希望这个URL被删除
so we do not want that URL to delete.
因此我们把这些设为nil
So we're going to set these to nil.
这样它们就不会在任何时候被删掉了
So that they won't get deleted at any point.
我们用它们 我们用那个URL
It's kind of like we use them, we use that URL,
我们现在只将它设为nil
so now we don't want to-- we want to just set it to nil.
这就是这里涉及到的一些清理任务
So that was that, that's the only clean-up there that was involved.
另外一点是Core Location错误检查
The other thing was this core location error checking,
可以看到 在shouldPerformForSegue中
and you can see, for example in our should perform for segue,
我在这里加了注释 "应该检查位置和imageURL"
I put a comment in here, "should check location and image URL" too, right?
因为我已经检查了 确保我们已经拍了照
Because I already checked to make sure we actually took a photo,
而且用户提供了标题 我还应该检查
and that the person provided a title, so I should also check
我们是否位置信息
that the location, that we got a location, right?
因为我们在后台获得的位置信息
Because remember that location we're kind of getting in the background
正在异步地从GPS
is asynchronously looking at GPS
wifi这些那里获取
or wi-fi or something to get that location.
这里 点完成时 我们要确保确实获得了位置信息
So here, when we hit "done," we've got to make sure we actually got one.
除了确保我们获得了位置信息之外
And more than just determining that we got it,
我们还要保证没有特定错误
let's make sure there wasn't a particular error.
这里有个办法可以监视错误
And so there's a way to watch for errors.
这里是我们创建位置管理器的地方
Here's where we create our location manager,
我们这里只使用了这一个委托方法
and we only use this one delegate method right here.
不过还有一点我们可以做
But there is another thing we could do,
也就是 我们可以实现这个委托方法
which is we could implement this delegate method,
didFailWithError
位置管理器失败时 它就会告诉我们
and that will tell us any time the location manager fails.
位置信息获取失败
Fails to get a location.
我将把这些进入到NSError的错误代码存起来
And I'm just going to salt away the error code that comes in this NS error
存入到这个locationErrorCode
into this location error code,
我把这设为一个属性
which I'm going to make a property.
这只是一个整数
Okay so it's just an integer.
我将保存这个错误代码
So I'm going to keep that error code,
然后在下面这里的完成中
and then down in done right here, okay,
除了检查是否有标题和是否拍过照之外
I am going to, in addition to checking the title and whether a photo was taken,
这里我还要检查是否获得了位置
here I'm going to check the location.
如果我没获得位置 如果位置为nil
And so if I didn't get a location, if location is nil,
那我就会去看我获得的错误代码
then I'm going to look at that error code that I got.
这里可能是0 也就是错误位置未知
Now, it might be zero, which is error location unknown,
这是什么意思呢
in which case, what does that mean if the location--
这里的错误是说
if either I've never gotten an error, or I got an error
错误位置未知 这里也就是0
and it said location unknown, which is zero,
这意味着它还在尝试
well, that means that it's still trying.
它还没得到错误说
It hasn't gotten an error
我无法获得位置 它还在尝试
that says I can't get the location, but it's still trying,
这时我们告诉用户
so that's what we're going to tell the user.
我现在还没弄清这张照片是在哪拍的
It's like I couldn't figure out where this photo was taken, yet.
用户看到这个警告会点OK
And if they say this is an alert, so they'll click "ok"
回到之前的位置
and they'll be back where they started,
用户可以再次点完成 他可以一直点下去
they can try hitting done again, and they just keep hitting done
看能不能得到 直到感到厌倦 然后点取消
and seeing if this keeps coming up until they get tired of it and they hit cancel.
这是一种错误情形
So that's one error situation.
另一种是被拒绝
Another one is "denied."
这个不应当发生 因为一开始我们就
This shouldn't happen because we checked whether we were
检验过是否有授权 记得吗
authorized before, at the very beginning remember?
如果没有授权 我们有一个致命警告
And we put a fatal alert up if you weren't authorized.
不过用户在看到这个警告后
But it's actually possible they could put this alert up,
有可能去设置 禁用它 回来 再点完成
go to settings, disable it, come back, and click "done,"
然后被拒绝
and then they'd be denied.
这很罕见 不过我们还是可以检查一下
So that's pretty rare, but let's check for it anyway.
如果用户这样做 我们可以告诉他
And if they do that, then we'll just tell them,
到隐私里面 把这个重新开启
go back into privacy and turn that thing back on.
我们可能被拒绝 很罕见 另一点是网络
So we could get a denied, rare, the other one is network,
我们尝试找到位置
so this is-- we're trying to find the location,
我们无法连上GPS 而且设备没有联网
we can't get any GPS, and they're not connected to the network,
我们不能使用wifi
so we can't use wi-fi either.
而且这里没有蜂窝网络
Or a cell site for that matter, okay,
这时 我们就真的碰到麻烦了
so now we're really stuck and the thing is
位置服务可以探测这种情况
that the location services can detect that case,
它会汇报这个错误 网络
and they'll actually report this error, network,
我们于是可以告诉用户 还是相同的基本错误
and we can tell the person still we can't-- same basic error,
我们无法获悉照片是在哪拍的 但至少我们可以建议
we can't figure out where the photo was taken, but at least we can suggest
请检验一下同网络的连接
that they verify your connection to the network.
用户可能发现自己忘记开wifi了 然后打开wifi
And oh, I forgot to turn wi-fi on, they turn wi-fi on, and oh,
这时就能找到位置了
now it's able to figure out their location.
否则 我们就只打算一般性地警告一下
And otherwise, we're just going to generically complain.
我们无法弄清位置
That we couldn't figure it out.
我这里只是想讲一下
So I just wanted to show you a little bit about getting
使用didFailWithError获得错误代码
that error code using this didFailWithError thing.
一般而言 课上的demo中
And in general, in demos that I do in this class,
我不会检查任何错误 这是出于时间考虑
obviously I hardly check any errors, it's just a time thing.
你们应该在任何获得NSError的时候
You should, any time you get an NS error back,
检查它到底是什么
you should go check it and see what it is,
去查查说明文档
and go look in the documentation and see what kind
看你得到什么错误 怎么处理它们
of errors you could get back and what you should do about them.
总记得这样做
Should always do that.
我在幻灯片中强调过 错误检查非常重要
I try to emphasize in the slides when errors are really important to check,
一般而言 我们总应该检查错误
but in general, we should always be checking those.
这就是这里我要讲的了
So that's it, that's all I wanted to show you there.
回到幻灯片
So back to our slides.
这方面有问题吗
Any questions about that?
请讲
Yeah?
问题是 苹果是否提供服务
So the question is, does Apple provide a service
让你能够对你获得的错误记录日志
where you can like log the errors you get, for what purpose,
这样你就知道…
to kind of so that they know what errors people are-- ?
哦 我懂你的意思了
Oh, I see what you mean, so you want to--
你的app的用户有了错误
you have customers for your app, and they're having errors,
你想知道这些
and you want to find out about them.
苹果没有提供这种功能
Apple doesn't provide that infrastructure,
不过有些第三方做了这个
but there are plenty of third parties who do.
这些第三方的代码可以放到你的app中
That basically provide code you put into your app
为此提供测量 不仅仅是错误
that provide metrics, not just errors,
还有用户点某个键多少次
but how many times did people click on this button?
用户去某个页面多少次 等等
How many times did they go to this page, you know, et cetera,
你可以看到用户如何在使用你的app
so you can see how people are using your app.
这其实很重要
That's actually quite important.
不过显然 这不是这堂课的讨论范围
Obviously beyond the scope of this app, or of this lecture,
不过我强烈建议app中进行一些测量
to talk about it, but I really highly recommend putting metrics
这样你就能理解真正的用户如何使用你的app
in your app so you really understand how your real users are actually using your app.
这样做工作量稍大一些 但很值得
It's a little more work for you, but it's really worth it.
好 再来看摄像头
Um, okay, so...the camera.
所有这些摄像头工作 以及将图像获取到app中
So all this camera business and basically getting images
都由这个类完成 UIImagePickerController
into your app is done with this class UIImagePickerController,
这是一个视图控制器
which is a view controller.
一个UIViewController 你会把它放到屏幕上
It's a UI view controller that you're going to put on screen,
可以是用模态 也可以是用弹窗
either modally or in a popover,
取决于你是在iPad还是iPhone上
depending on whether you're in iPad or iPhone, and you're--
这是你们第一次使用这样的视图控制器
so this is the first time you're going to have a view controller
它不来自于故事板
that didn't come out of a storyboard.
这个视图控制器你将需要alloc init
This view controller you're going to alloc init, alright?
然后你想把它放到屏幕上
And then you're going to want to put it on screen,
你需要使用几周前我讲过的这个方法
so you're going to have to use this method that we did talk about weeks ago
当时我们讲到presenting view controller
when we talked about presenting view controllers called
也就是presentViewController animated
"present view controller, animated."
completion
Completion.
它还有一个完成block
It's got a completion block as well.
这就是我们把这个放到屏幕上的方式
And so that's how we're going to put this thing on screen.
present视图控制器的参数是一个视图控制器
And the argument to present view controller is a view controller,
不是视图控制器的故事板标识符
not a storyboard identifier for a view controller,
而是视图控制器的实例
but an actual instance of a view controller.
然后iPad上
And then the iPad you're probably going to put
使用摄像头时可能需要模态全屏
the camera-- actually the iPad you probably put the camera up full-screen modally,
如果只是查照片库
if you're just looking at the photo library, you're going
你可能就只需要弹窗
to probably put that up in a popover.
这如何工作呢
Alright, so how does this work?
你alloc init这个UIImagePickerController
You alloc and init this UIImagePickerController,
设置它的委托 这是必需的
you set it's delegate, you have to set it's delegate
否则什么信息都无法得到
or you're not going to get any information out of it.
然后你可以进行配置 包括摄像头
Then you configure it for what you want, the camera,
或照片库这些
or photo library, things like that,
是否让用户在拍照后进行编辑
whether you're going to let the user edit the photo after they take it.
然后present它 监听委托 当委托告诉你
Then you present it, and listen to the delegate, and when the delegate tells you
用户取消了或拍了照片
that the user has either canceled or taken a photo,
如果拍了照片 你就能获得图像数据
then you, if they've taken a photo you get the image data,
如果取消了 你就知道事情完了
and if they cancel you're like "Okay well they're done."
在UIImagePickerController 用户可以做什么
Alright? What the user can do in this UIImagePickerController,
取决于其硬件能做什么
it depends on what their hardware can do.
几乎所有设备现在都有摄像头了
Almost everything has a camera now, so you're usually--
这不成问题 isSourceTypeAvailable
if this is going to be no problem, source type available,
摄像头 你将能够找到它
camera, you're going to find it,
不过这个还是应该检查
but you should always check this anyway.
养成好的习惯很有必要
Just to kind of, to be good code,
你要调用UIImagePickerController
you want to call this UIImagePickerController,
类方法是isSourceTypeAvailable
class method is source type available,
上次的demo中我们其实做过
and we actually did that in our demo last time.
记得吧 我们有一个类方法canAddPhoto
Remember? We had that class method can add photo,
其中 我们检查以确保
and in there we checked to make sure
摄像头实际可用
that the camera was actually available,
这就是做法 用这个类方法
so this is how you do it, just this class method,
来自UIImagePickerController
UIImagePickerController.
知道摄像头可用之后 如果你想拍摄视频
Once you know the camera is available, then if you want to take video,
那你就需要确保其摄像头可以拍视频
you need to be able to make sure that camera can do video,
因为有些老设备上的摄像头不能拍视频
because there are cameras in older devices that can't take video,
只能拍照片
they can only take images.
做法是通过这个类方法
And you do that with this class method,
availableMediaTypesForSourceType
"available media types for source type,"
sourceType是摄像头
and the source type is the camera.
它会告诉你 它会返回一个数组
So it's going to tell you, what are, it's going to give you an array back
涉及到这个摄像头能做什么
of what things this camera can do.
你会得到这两个常量或其中之一
And you're only going to have one of two or both
一个是kUTTypeImage 一个是kUTTypeMovie
of these two constants, UT type image, and UT type movie,
很不幸 这两个常量来自于
unfortunately, these two constants come
MobileCoreServices/MobileCoreServices.h
from MobileCoreServices, MobileCoreServices.h,
它们不在Foundation或UIKit中
they're not in foundation or UI kits,
因此你需要明确导入这个
so you have to explicitly import this thing.
你需要连入MobileCoreServices
You've got to link in the MobileCoreServices,
不过在iOS7的新机制中
but with the new mechanism in iOS7,
这个会自动地为你连入
that should get linked in for you automatically.
很不幸 kUTTypeImage和kUTTypeMovie这两个常量
And unfortunately, those two things, kUTType image and kUTType movie
并不是NSString
are not NS strings,
它们是Core Foundation字符串
they are core foundation strings,
几张幻灯片后 我们就会谈到如何在代码中处理这个
so we'll talk about how we deal with that in our code in a couple slides here.
你还可以查到前置和后置摄像头
You can also find out about front-facing versus rear-facing cameras,
硬件的各种细节内容都可以从
all kinds of details about what your hardware has, just take a look
UIImagePickerController的说明文档中查到
at the documentation for UIImagePickerController and you can find that all out.
有问题
Is that a question?
视图控制器会提供UI
Uh, the view controller will provide UI
让其从前置摄像头或后置摄像头选取
for them to pick front camera or back camera,
不过你可以说 只让其自拍
but you can also say only let them take a selfie, right?
你知道我说的什么吗
Only for, or whatever, you know what I'm saying?
你可以这样决定 不过他们也有…
You can just determine it, but they also have the--
如果你不决定 那么他们就能选择
if you don't determine it, then they can choose.
答案是肯定的
So the answer is yes.
好 下面这是
Alright, so this is what it looks
ImagePickerController的配置
like to configure the ImagePickerController here,
我创建了一个 设置了委托
so I'm creating one, I'm setting my delegate,
检查源类型 看摄像头能不能…
I'm checking the source type to see if the camera,
这里我要用视频 因此我要确保
I want to do video here, so I'm going to make sure
它能拍视频 如果能拍 那就好了
that it does video, and if it does, I'm ready to go.
这里是用一些代码
So that's a summary of what I just said,
总结了一下我刚讲的几张幻灯片
kind of in-code what I just said on the last few slides.
下面我们来谈谈kUTTypeImage和kUTTypeMovie
Um, so let's talk about that kUTType movie and kUTType image,
它们是CFString
they are CF strings.
你可以把它们转为NSString
You can just cast them to NS strings.
Core Foundation和你们更熟悉的Foundation间
There is a bridging mechanism between core foundation and foundation,
有很好的桥梁机制
which is what you're used to.
这里在iOS6或7中 你可以进行强制类型转换
And so you can just put this cast in here, and in iOS6 or 7,
这里可以自动给你转换类型
they introduced a thing where it will even do this bridging
for you automatically in terms of arc and all that,
这里可以直接转换
so you just need to cast that, it's just something you need
只需要将NSString *放到那两个之前即可
to know, is to put the NS string star in front of those two types.
可编辑性 用户用摄像头拍照时
Alright, editability-- so when someone takes a picture with the camera,
可以放大
they can actually zoom in on it,
选择图像的某一部分
and move around and pick what part of the image they want
并汇报回app 如果你允许的话
to report back to your app, if you allow that.
允许这个需要使用allowsEditing
And you have to allow that by saying allows editing
用到UIImagePickerController实例
to your UIImagePickerController instance,
你还可以限制视频捕捉
and you can also do things like limit the video capture
让其只能低画质拍摄 或是只能拍摄特定秒数
to be low resolution or only a certain number of seconds, things like that.
UIImagePicker中的细节我不打算一一讲到
So I'm not going to go through every single thing you can do in UIImagePicker,
不过flash方面 还有很多事情你可以做
but there's tons and tons of stuff you can do with flash,
你可以控制很多东西
all these other things you can control.
有了这个UIImagePickerController
So then, you have this UIImagePickerController
你可以将自己实例化为它的委托 然后你可以present它
that you've instantiated yourself as the delegate of, now you present it.
在iPad上 如果你没有提供摄像头
And so on the iPad, if you're not offering the camera,
如果你… 抱歉 这里我们有些掩盖了真相
so if you're-- sorry, we kind of glossed over this a little bit--
你可以让用户用摄像头拍照
you can offer to get a picture from the camera,
也可以让用户从照片库中选照片
or you can also offer the user to have a picture come from their photo library.
这就是设备上app中的管理方式
Which is this thing they manage in app on their device.
你可以选两者或其中之一
And so you can kind of pick either or both.
在iPhone上 你可以同时要两者
On the iPhone, you can ask for both at the same time,
它会给出一个UI 用户可以在两者中进行选择
so it will put up a UI where you can kind of-- the user can pick between the two.
在iPad上 你不会这样做
On the iPad you don't do it that way.
在iPad上 要么是摄像头 要么是照片库
On the iPad it's camera or photo library
因为照片库会放到弹窗中
because the photo library you're going to bring up in a popover,
而摄像头则是全屏模态
the camera you're probably going to do full-screen modal.
这就是通常不把两者同时混起来的原因
So that's why you're usually not mixing them at the same time.
用户用摄像头拍照或是从照片库中选择照片后
After the user has chosen a photo from by using the camera
or from their photo library,
你就会得到这个委托方法 imagePickerController
you're going to get this delegate method, ImagePickerController,
didFinishPickingMediaWithInfo
didFinishPickingMediaWithInfo.
然后你就要消掉那个视图控制器
And you are then going to dismiss that view controller.
你需要手动消掉它
So you have to manually dismiss it right here,
在消掉它之前
but before you dismiss it, you're going to look
你需要看刚刚传递的信息字典
into that dictionary that just passed, this info dictionary,
并获得关于摄像头的信息 关于用户拍了什么照片等等
and get the information about what camera, what picture they took or whatever.
如果用户点了摄像头上的取消
If they didn't, if they hit cancel on the camera,
那你就会得到imagePickerControllerDidCancel
then you're just going to get this imagePickerControllerDidCancel,
这样就没有信息字典
and there's no info dictionary there,
你无法获悉任何关于照片的信息
so you don't get to find anything about the photo.
如果是在弹窗中 你就需要使用
Again, if you're in a popover, you're going to use the
弹窗的didDismissPopover…委托方法
popover did dismiss popover business,
你会做相同的事情
you'll do the same thing.
返回的字典中有些什么呢
So what's in that dictionary that you get back?
如果用户didFinishPickingMediaWithInfo
So if the user did finish picking with info,
其中有什么呢
what's in it,
有用户拍的照片
there's the image that they took.
包括放大和裁剪后的图像
Both the edited image, if they zoomed in and cropped it,
和没有编辑的原图
and the original image, if they didn't--
whether they did or not, the original image is in there.
如果有裁剪 它会告诉你是沿图像内哪个矩形裁剪的
If they cropped it, it will tell you the rectangle inside the image that they cropped to.
如果是视频 你会得到视频文件的URL
If it's a video, you're going to get a URL to a file, with the video in there.
这就是你得到视频的方式 文件URL
So that's how video comes back to you, as a URL to some file.
得到了这些图像 如果你想保存它们
And you can, if you get these images, and you want
例如存到用户的照片库
to save them, like in the user's photo library,
这是ALAssetsLibrary中的API
that's--  API is in AL assets library.
我不打算讲这个 不过API就在这里
Not going to cover that, but that's where the API is,
如果你想把用户拍的照片存入到照片库
if you want to save it into their photo library. Some picture they've taken.
和Photomania中一样 我们不打算做这个
Like in PhotoMania, we're not going to do that,
我们会把它存入我们自己的数据库
we're actually going to save it into our own database, but--
而且我们会把图像存入我们的文档目录
and we're going to save our image into our documents directory,
不过我们也可以在照片库中做些什么
but we could put things in the photo library as well.
摄像头可以有一个覆盖视图在它之上
The camera can have an overlay view on top of it.
这是在它之上的视图
This is a view that sits on top of it.
你还可以提供你自己的按钮
You can even provide your own buttons for like
用于"拍照"这些
"take picture" and things like that.
这只是一个视图
This is just a view,
你还可以得到这个变形 看到底部了吗
and you also are going to get this transform, see at the bottom there?
cameraViewTransform
Camera view transform,
有时你可能希望用户拍的照片放大到全屏
in case you want the image that the person's taking, for example, to be scaled
因为手机本身的纵横比有可能不同于照片
up to full screen, because the aspect ratio of the phone
这样它就不能全屏显示
itself is not the same as the camera, so it won't be full screen.
旁边会看到边框
You'll see there will kind of be some borders around it,
有些人喜欢放大到全屏 这时可以变形
when people like to zoom it up to full screen, you could do the transform to do that.
如果在覆盖视图中
If, in your overlay view,
你要提供"拍照"按钮
you provide the "take picture" button,
那么你就要说 "显示摄像头控制 不"
then you want to say "show camera controls, no"
否则你就会从iOS获得拍照按钮
otherwise you'll have the take picture button from iOS
还有你自己的拍照按钮
and also your own take picture button.
覆盖 你们也可以离线去看这些
So overlays, you can look those up offline as well.
demo中我不打算考虑
We're not going to do those in the demo.
让我们把拍照这个环节加到Photomania中
Let's go ahead and add this photo taking to PhotoMania.
这个动作表单 看看时间够不够再作考虑
And this action sheet thing, we'll see how the time goes, whether we do the action sheet.
这是我们的Photomania
Alright, so here we are in PhotoMania,
记得吧 让我们到这里
and if you remember here, let's go ahead and go over here...
回想一下它是怎样的
and remind ourselves what it looked like right now...
这是My Photos 我们还没有拍任何照片
So we have our photos here, we haven't taken any photos yet.
但愿这是在后台加载
Hopefully, this is probably loading in the background
好 有了 从Flickr
as well, yeah, there it is, from Flickr.
看My Photos 里面什么都还没有
But if I look at my photos, I can see I don't have any,
不过右上角有相机
but I have the camera in the corner, so I'm going
点它 我们把照片放进来
to press the camera, we put that photo in.
这里可以看到提示说
And see you notice it saying "PhotoMania would
Photomania要使用当前位置
like to use your current location" okay?
我点OK 如果我说不
And I'm going to say "Ok," if I said "no,"
这里或许就会出现致命错误 说我无法拍照
we probably would have to put up this fatal error that says you can't take a picture.
这里我们想这样 看到拍照按钮了吗
And what we want to do here is you see the "take photo" button?
我想按那个拍照按钮时
I want to be able to press that "take photo" button
UIImagePickerController出现
and have this UIImagePickerController come up.
这就是我们接下来要做的事
So that's what we're going to do next.
拍照 我们其实已经关联起来了
Alright, so take photo, we actually wired that up
在我们最开始的时候 放到哪里了
when we very first started here, where did we put it?
在这里
It is right...here.
它现在什么都做不了
And it doesn't do anything right now.
这里我们需要做什么呢
So what do we need to do here?
刚才幻灯片里我讲的所有那些事情
All those things I just told you in this slide.
我们说 UIImagePickerController
So let's do a UIImagePickerController,
uiipc
UIImagePickerController, UI,
= UIImagePickerController alloc init
image picker controller equals UIImagePickerController, alloc init.
这里只是alloc init
So we just alloc init,
不需在初始化时指定任何其它东西
there is no other thing we specify when we initialize it,
我们只需要做这些
that's all we need to do.
然后 我们只需要设置这个UIImagePickerController
And then we just need to set up this UIImagePickerController
来指定我们的选项
to specify any options we have.
我们还需要把自己设置为委托
And we also need to set ourselves as the delegate.
首先来做这个
So I'm going to do that first.
你会看到这里很有趣
And you're going to see something interesting about this.
我们知道 将自己设为委托后
So we know that as soon as we set ourselves as a delegate,
我们会得到这个警告说
we're going to get this warning that says
我们没有实现UIImagePickerControllerDelegate方法
we don't implement the UIImagePickerControllerDelegate method.
注意 它还说 我们没有实现
Notice it also says we don't implement the
UINavigationControllerDelegate
UINavigationControllerDelegate.
对于UIImagePickerController 这很奇怪
This is kind of a weird thing about the UIImagePickerController,
它继承自UINavigationController
it inherits from UINavigationController,
因此它继承了那个委托方法 因此它需要
so it inherits that delegate method, and so it requires
你成为两者的委托
that you be a delegate for both.
因此我需要是NavigationControllerDelegate
So I have to be NavigationControllerDelegate,
同时还是ImagePickerControllerDelegate
and I have to be the ImagePickerControllerDelegate.
这两者都没有任何必需的方法
Now neither of those things have any mandatory methods,
义务并不繁重 不过对于这个错误 很多人都会说
so it's not that onerous but this is just an error that a lot of people are like, "Huh?
为什么要说这个
Why is it saying that?"
这是UIImagePickerController方面很奇特的一点
It's just a weird thing about UIImagePickerController,
你需要成为NavigationControllerDelegate
you have to be a NavigationControllerDelegate.
你不需要实现任何方法
You're not going to implement any of those methods,
你只需要实现那个协议
just have to say you do implement that protocol.
现在 我们是委托
So now we're the delegate, and we're going
我们等下会实现一些方法
to implement a couple of those methods in a minute, but first,
不过首先 我要完成这个的配置
I'm going to finish configuring this thing.
我还要做什么
So what else am I going to do?
我要说 我想要怎样的媒体类型
Well, I'm going to say what media types I want,
我唯一想要的媒体类型是图像
and the only media type I want is an image.
我不需要视频 这里是kUTTypeImage
I don't want video, so, kUTType what's it called, image? Image. Yeah.
这是一个数组
So this is an array,
不过这里只有这一个东西 我进行了这个奇特的类型转换
but the only one I'm putting in there is this one thing, and I'm doing this weird cast.
然后 这里我还要设置什么呢
And then what else do I want to set up here?
我想要设置源类型 这里我要的是摄像头
I want to set up the source type, which is I want the camera.
这是ImagePickerControllerSourceTypeCamera
So this is ImagePickerController, SourceType, Camera.
这里我还可以说 竖线
Now, I could also say here vertical bar
UIImagePickerSourceTypePhotoLibrary
UIImagePicker SourceType PhotoLibrary.
在iPhone上 这没问题
On the iPhone this would be fine,
UI可以让我选择这两个地方的任一个
where the UI would let me choose from either of these two places.
我的demo机器上没有照片库
I don't have anything in my photo library on my demo
这里可以说是有些浪费
machine, so it's kind of a waste.
iPad上 我就需要分开做两个UI了
And on the iPad I would have to do two separate UIs,
我就不能这样做了
so I couldn't really do that there anyway.
我还要允许编辑 为什么不呢
I'm also going to allow editing, why not?
allowsEditing = YES
Allows editing equals yes, so that allows me to crop
这让我能对图像进行裁剪和缩放
and zoom in, allows the user to crop and zoom in on the image.
就这些了
And that's it.
然后我只需要使用presentViewController
And now I just do this PresentViewController.
animated:YES
Animated, yes.
completion 这个完成block
Completion-- completion block, again,
会在viewDidAppear发生时立刻被调用 换言之
it would get called as soon as the view did appear happened, so in other words,
它一到屏幕上 这个就会被调用
once it was on screen, this would get called,
我甚至不需要做任何事情
I don't need to do anything then.
这就完成了
So we're done.
这会导致一个模态视图控制器出现
So this is going to cause a modal view controller
它会占据屏幕 这将是相机
to appear, and it takes over the screen, and it's going to be the camera,
用户可以选择是使用拍摄的照片
and the user's either going to have the option of using the photo they take
还是点取消
or hitting cancel.
两种情况我们都要处理
So we have to handle both those cases.
首先来看取消这种情况 因为这很简单
So let's do the cancel case first, because it's really easy.
我们可以用这个来做到
And we do that with this one right here...this is right here,
imagePickerControllerDidCancel
ImagePickerController DidCancel.
这里只有两个方法 有一个已经过时
You can see there's only two methods here, there's an old deprecated one there,
but there's only these two.
我们将会实现这两个
Those are the two we're going to implement.
在取消中 我们只需要消掉这个东西
So in cancel, our only responsibility is to dismiss this thing.
因为我们不打算使用照片这些
Because we're not going to use the photo or anything like that,
因此这里说dismiss…:YES 还是completion
so I'm going to say dismiss, yes, completion again,
这里我不需要完成处理器
I don't need the completion handler there.
这个很简单
So that's an easy one.
然后是另一个
And then the other one,
这个 这是didFinishPickingMediaWithInfo
this guy...this is the DidFinishPickingMedia WithInfo,
我们有这个字典
so we've got this dictionary right here,
提供用户选择的照片的信息
that provides the information about the photo that the user chose.
这里用户确实选择了照片
So the user did choose a photo in this case.
这个也很简单
So this one's easy too.
我们只需要说image =
We're just going to say image equals
info[UIImagePickerControllerEditedImage]
info UIImagePickerController, edited image.
这是到这个字典中的键
So this is a key into this dictionary.
这是编辑过的图像 UIImage被用户编辑过
Right? And that's the edited image, the UI image the user edited.
我还要说 if (!image)
Now, I'm also going to say if not image,
那么image就等于
then the image equals
info[UIImagePickerControllerOriginalImage]
the info UIImagePickerController original image.
为什么这样做呢
Why am I doing this?
因为这里我允许编辑
Because I allow editing right here.
我知道我会得到这张编辑过的图像
So I know I'm going to get this edited image.
以后我可能会把这转为NO 这时我的代码就会中断
Well, someday I might turn this to no, and then my code here would break.
我只是希望我的代码在两种情况下都能使用
So I'm just trying to make code here that would work in either case.
这一行代码对我而言很轻松就能搞定
It costs no skin off my nose to put this line of code in here,
而且这能让它转变为NO时也能工作
and it will make it so if it ever changes to no, then this is going to still work.
就算我不这样 也不会有什么损失
Doesn't hurt me if I don't.
我有了图像 下面我说 self.image = image
Alright, so I got the image, so I'm just going to self.image equals image,
记得吧 我们设置过这个属性
remember that we have this property set
我们实现了setter和getter 在这里
that we implement the setter and getter for, which is right here.
这里设置了图像视图的图像
Which is just setting the image view's image.
如果我们设置新东西
If we're setting it to something new,
那么旧URL就要被删除 今天我已经演示过了
then it's deleting the old URL, we showed that already today.
我们设置好图像 然后dismiss
So...we set our image, and then we dismiss.
就是这样了
And that's it.
使用摄像头是很简单的
So using the camera, quite straightforward.
只要你理解了委托这些东西
Once you understand that you have to do this delegate thing
来获得这里的结果 这就非常简单了
to get the results out of there, it's pretty straightforward.
我们来试试这个
So let's try and see if we can make this work.
这里要拍张照片
Here something to take a picture of here.
到My Photos 到这里 拍张照片
Alright, so we'll go to My Photos, I'm going to go here, and I'm going to take a photo.
我们会得到这个ImagePickerController
We're going to get this ImagePickerController that's
它会模态式地出现 这是我的照片控制器
going to come up Modally, so here's my picture controller,
2002 这有些老了 拍张它的照片
2002, that's kind of old, but take it. So I'm just going to take this picture.
有点模糊 重新拍一张
Alright? That's a little blurry, so I'll take another one.
这个好些了
That's a little better.
我还可以放大
And I could zoom in here, if I want.
剪切 因为我允许用户编辑
Crop it, because I've allowed user editing, right?
我们可以这样
So we can do that.
拍完照之后 点使用照片
And then once I got it the way I want it, hit "use photo"
它就会返回到图像视图中
and it comes back and sets in our image view.
这里我们还需要输入标题
One thing we also need to do is put in a title there,
快速输个名字
but that's...let's do that real quick.
Giants 好 有了
Giants. Alright. Okay. There we go.
这是照片 这是我们的缩略图
So now hopefully our photo, there's our thumbnail,
点击 可以看到细节
if we click, we can see the detail of it.
这方面有问题吗
Any questions about that?
很简单 摄像头这些东西
It's pretty straightforward, the camera thing.
看还有多少时间
Alright. Let's see what time we've got.
最后我会回头讲动作表单
I'm going to come back to doing the action sheet at the end,
因为我想首先讲Core Motion
because I really want to show you this other stuff first, the core motion stuff,
而动作表单 你们大部分是懂的
and the action sheet, I think you mostly understand that,
因此 我们最后再回来考虑
so we'll come back to this later.
回到幻灯片
So let's go keynote here, okay.
好 Core Motion
Alright. So core motion.
Core Motion是用于访问设备硬件的API
So, core motion is the API for accessing the hardware
告诉你关于运动的信息
on your device that tells you about motion.
设备上感觉运动的硬件其实有很多
And there's a lot of different pieces of hardware,
actually, that senses motion on your device,
有些设备的硬件比其它更多
and some devices have more hardware than others.
适当地使用Core Motion能让你
So a lot of using core motion properly is kind
理解设备有些什么 如何使用
of understanding what your device has, and how you're going to use it,
如果没有相关硬件 你是否仍能做你想做的事
and if it doesn't have things, can you still do what you want to do?
也许不能做得原来那么好 等等
Maybe not quite as nicely, et cetera.
设备运动的主要输入包括加速计
But, the primary inputs to where--
to the motion of your device, are the accelerometer,
它会告诉你设备的加速度
which is just telling you the acceleration of your device,
在x y和z方向
in X, Y, and Z.
陀螺仪 让你知道什么时候设备在旋转
A gyro, which is letting the device know when it's being rotated,
这是很重要的信息
which is an important thing for it to know,
还有磁力计 告诉你真北在哪
and magnetometer, which is telling it "where is true north?"
实际上 它知道磁北在哪
So really it knows where magnetic north is,
不过只要它知道GPS位置 它也能知道真北
but if it knows your GPS location, then it knows where true north is as well.
用于获得这些设备信息的类
So...the class that you use to get this information
叫作CMMotionManager
about your device is called CM Motion Manager, kind of similar
有些类似于CLLocationManager
to this CL Location Manager,
CLLocationManager让我知道设备处于什么地方
which is how we got where the device is in the world,
CMMotionManager可以通过alloc init来创建
and you create it just with alloc init.
这个需要稍微小心一些
You have to be a little careful with this thing,
因为你不能在app中有两个不同的地方
because you can't really have two different places in your app
alloc init这种东西
alloc initting one of these things
并要求不同的信息率这些
and asking for different information rates or something like that,
因为它汇报信息的频率
because the rate at which it's going to report its information
需要在整个应用程序中都达成一致
really is something that your whole application needs to be on the same page about.
你不希望应用中一个地方
So you wouldn't want one place
获得信息非常非常快
in your application getting data really really fast,
做一些微调得很好的事 而另一个地方很慢
because it's doing some really fine-tuned thing, and the other wants it really slow,
这就会不同步
and then they're kind of out of sync.
有些人会认为
So some people would argue
CMMotionManager应该是全局的
that CM Motion Manager should just be global.
应该在全局某处 有些类变量
You should have some global somewhere, some class variable,
或是app委托这些
or your app delegate or something.
我不知道有没有必要那样
I don't know that that's strictly necessary to go
不过这里确实是很有争议的地方
that far, but it is something where they can fight each other,
做这个时需要小心
so you've got to be careful about doing that.
这是因为只有一台设备
And that's just really because there's only one device,
而且只有一个陀螺仪和一个加速计
and there's only one gyro and one accelerometer,
某种意义上讲 作为全局资源是有意义的
and so it makes sense that this is a global resource, in a sense.
如何使用MotionManager呢
So how to use the Motion Manager?
同LocationManager类似
Just like Location Manager,
首先检查有什么硬件可用
you check to see what hardware is available, then you kind
然后具体怎么做 有两种选项
of have two choices to how you want to do it.
你可以进行一些取样
You can set some sampling going,
然后对MotionManager进行poll(探寻)
and then poll the Motion Manager.
例如 三个方向上 基于重力的当前加速度是多少
What's the current acceleration due to gravity
in these three directions, for example.
我不喜欢poll
Polling we don't like.
我有一张幻灯片讲过 我不赞成这样
I have a slide on that, but you can see I'm going to blast right
因为poll不是很好
by it, because polling-- not so good--
第二种方式是在队列上放一个block
as the second way, which is that you basically put a block on a queue
按照你指定的频率被调用
that will get called every time, at whatever rate you say,
告诉你 基于重力的当前加速度是多少
to tell you here's the current acceleration to gravity, here's the current...
它会不断告诉你
just tell you over and over and over,
你可以设置这个发生的频率 这是更好的做法
and you can set the rate at which that's happening-- much better way to do that.
尤其是你可以让那个block在另一个队列上执行
Especially since you can have that block be executing on another queue.
收集数据 进行合并等等
Collecting the data, coalescing it, whatever,
然后回头同主队列通信
and then communicating back to the main queue,
也许是以较低频率 这里它在更新UI
maybe at a lower rate, where it's updating the UI.
这就是我们主要要关注的
So mostly that's what we're going to focus on,
也就是发布一个block到队列
is the way of posting a block to a queue.
如何检查可用性呢
So how do you check the availability?
CMMotionManager中有这样的属性
There is this property in CMMotionManager
叫accelerometerAvailable
called accelerometer available,
gyroAvailable magnetometerAvailable
gyro available, magnetometer available,
然后是非常重要的deviceMotionAvailable
and then the very important device motion available,
等下我们会谈到这个
and we will talk about that in a second.
如何开启这些感应器呢
How do you start up these sensors?
如果你不调用startAccelerometerUpdates
If you don't call start accelerometer updates,
它就不会给你任何更新
it will not give you any updates.
poll时 你就不会得到任何最新信息
And when you poll, you won't get any update-- any information that's up to date.
你需要开启它
So you have to start it.
一般 我们不会这样在poll中开启它
Now, normally we're not going to start it this way in poll,
我们会通过给它一个block来开启
we're going to start it by giving it a block
以我们规定的频率进行调用
to go call us every time, you know, at whatever rate.
总之 我们需要开启它 理解这一点很重要
But we do need to start it. It's important to understand you have to start it.
不开启就无法获得数据
If you don't start it, you get no data.
你还可以弄清
You can also find out,
硬件当前在没在收集数据
is the hardware currently collecting data?
换言之 加速计是否开启并在收集数据
In other words, is the accelerometer on and collecting data?
陀螺仪是否开启并在收集数据
Is the gyro on and collecting data?
这些也可以知道
So you can find out that as well.
很重要的是 你也可以终止它这样做
And very importantly, you can stop it doing this.
为什么说重要呢
Why is that important?
因为这些东西的耗电量很大
These things aren't free when it comes to battery.
测量加速度 陀螺仪测量 测量位置 这些都会耗电
Measuring the acceleration, measuring the gyro, position, all of that, it takes power.
不用的时候 你需要关掉它
And so you want to turn it off when you're not using it.
同CLLocationManager一样
Just exactly like the CLLocationManager, right?
不使用时关掉它
Turn it off when you're not using it.
这是poll
So here's the polling thing.
这张幻灯片我不打算细讲
I have this slide, we're not really going to look at it,
不过对于这每个 加速计 陀螺仪
but for each of the things, accelerometer, gyro,
磁力计和设备运动都可以poll
magnetometer, and device motion,
设备运动这个很神奇 我马上会讲到
which is the magic one I'm going to talk about in a moment here, you can poll
你都可以问 当前状态是什么
and say "what's the current state of this?"
但一般我们不这样做
But you don't usually do that.
然后我要讲那个神奇的东西
And now I'm going to talk about the magic thing
然后再谈论将block发布到队列
before we talk about posting the blocks on the queues,
这里我要讲的是CMDeviceMotion
which is CMDeviceMotion.
有了陀螺仪 加速计
If you had a gyro and an accelerometer
还有磁力计 你就对设备的位置很了解了
and a magnetometer, you really know a lot about this device's position.
很了解
Really a lot!
实际上 你可以同时使用多个设备
And in fact, you can use multiple of those devices together
来获得更好的信息
to get better information.
例如 我们考虑加速
For example, let's talk about acceleration.
这里有个加速计
Really, there's an accelerometer in there,
它总是在测量由于重力的加速
it's always measuring the acceleration due to gravity,
也就是9.8米每秒平方
which is 9.8 meters per second squared.
如果你问原始加速计 该设备的当前加速度是多少
So if you ask the raw accelerometer what's the current acceleration of this device?
它总会回答你说是 1g 指向地球的中心
It's always going to give you 1 G down toward the center of the earth.
无论发生了什么
No matter what's actually happening.
如果你像这样握住设备
Now, if you are holding your device like this,
然后像这样 其它方向也会有加速度
and you're going like this, you're also going to have acceleration in these other axes,
但加速计还是只有指向下面的那个
but you're always going to have that one pointing down.
这就让你很难弄清
So it's kind of like it's a little bit difficult for you
用户实际在用设备做什么
to then figure out what's the user actually doing with my device?
因为你需要使用低通过滤器来滤出
You see? Because you kind of have to filter out with like a low pass filter,
来自于重力的加速度
the acceleration due to gravity.
如果有陀螺仪 你就不需要这样
Well, you don't have to do that if you have a gyro.
因为只要有陀螺仪
Because if you have a gyro,
你就知道设备现在有没有倾斜
you know whether the device is tilted now.
知道有没有倾斜 你就能够剔除
And since you know whether it's tilted, you can factor
基于重力的加速度在哪 明白了吗
out where the acceleration due to gravity is, you see?
CMDeviceMotion是另一个你可以询问的东西
Right? And so the CMDeviceMotion is another thing you can ask
就像你可以询问加速计和陀螺仪一样
for, just like you can ask for the accelerometer or you can ask for the gyro,
你也可以询问这个神奇的CMDeviceMotion
you can ask for this magic CMDeviceMotion,
它实际上是其它那些东西的融合
it's actually a conglomeration of those other things.
例如 它可以告诉你
And so for example it can tell you what is the
剔除重力后 加速度是多少
acceleration of the device with gravity taken out.
CMDeviceMotion中有个属性叫userAcceleration
So there's a property in the CMDeviceMotion called User Acceleration,
这是设备的加速度 不包括重力
which is the acceleration of the device, not including gravity.
你可以弄清重力指向哪里
You can also find out where gravity is pointing based
基于设备的当前朝向
on the device's current orientation.
类似地 设备的旋转会有偏差
Similarly, there's bias in there for rotation of the device.
这来自于设备的电子特性
Bias due to electronics of the device.
也可以通过加速计来剔除
That can be taken out using the accelerometer.
陀螺仪汇报信息可以得到加速计的辅助
So the gyros reported information can also be helped
它们之间可以互相帮助
by the accelerometer, so they kind of help each other,
你还可以得到设备位置的更精密信息
and you can also get more sophisticated answers about the position of the device,
例如横滚 俯仰和偏向
like roll, pitch and yaw.
都知道横滚 俯仰和偏向吗
You all know what roll, pitch and yaw is?
横滚是这样 偏向是这样 俯仰是这样
Roll is this way, yaw is like this, pitch is like this.
你可以获得所有这些信息 这就像是一架飞机一样
So now you really can find out where, like almost this is an airplane, right?
你可以发现空间中的横滚 俯仰和偏向
You can find it's roll, pitch and yaw in space.
这些都能够知道 只要你知道重力在哪
And those are all possible when you know where gravity is,
真北在哪
if you know where true north is,
你有一个参考点 等等
you kind of have a reference point, all those things.
CMDeviceMotion的作用就是
So CMDeviceMotion, that's where you're going
在空间中进行精密的位置分析
to do any sophisticated analysis of things to position in space.
你们可以去看说明文档 里面有各种属性
And you can go look at the documentation, you can see already right there some
包括横滚 俯仰和偏向 旋转率 用户加速度
of the properties you can get, roll, pitch and yaw, rotation rate, user acceleration.
所有这些都来自于CMDeviceMotion
All those things come out of a CMDeviceMotion.
如果你在一个没有陀螺仪的设备上
Now, if you're on a device that doesn't have a gyro,
CMDeviceMotion还在
the CMDeviceMotion is going to be there,
有些东西会给你未确定的结果
but some things are going to give you unspecified results,
例如用户加速度就无法确定
like user acceleration can't be determined
没有陀螺仪的设备就是这样了
on a device where there's no gyro.
它会给你重力加速度
It will give you the acceleration due to gravity,
但你得不到用户加速度
but can't give you the user acceleration.
你需要知道
So you have to know.
这就是你需要检查设备有些什么的原因
That's why you have to check what your device has.
如何做block这些呢
So...how do we do this block thing?
我想要开启我的设备 检查加速计的情况
So I want to start my device, checking what is going on with the accelerometer,
我想要它汇报给我 发生了什么
and I want it to report to me what's going on.
做法是 我会给它一个block
And the way I do that is I give it a block,
一个CMAccelerometerHandler block 这里
a CM Accelerometer Handler block right there.
看它是如何定义的 它有一个参数
You can see how it's defined, it takes an argument,
这是CMAcceleratorData 然后还有这个错误
which is the CM Accelerator data, and in this error,
它会按照你指定的频率不断调用这个block
and it just keeps calling that block over and over at whatever rate you tell it to.
下一张幻灯片上我会具体说明如何设置
And we'll talk about how you set that on the next slide.
这可以用于加速计更新
And you can do that for accelerometer updates,
可以用于陀螺仪更新 也可以用于设备运动
you can do it for gyro updates, you can do it for device motion as well.
横滚 俯仰和偏向这些 也能通过这个得到
That roll, pitch and yaw, all that, it will tell you that.
不能再简单了 你只用调用这个方法
So couldn't be simpler, you just call this method
startAccelerometer或GyroUpdatesToQueue
start, accelerometer or gyro, updates to queue,
你给它一个队列
you give it a queue.
这个队列 如果你要它更新的频率很低
Now, that queue, if your rate at which you're asking it
你可以把它设为主队列
to tell you is pretty low, that can be the main queue.
什么叫低呢
And what do I mean by low?
你可以自己判断 如果是60次每秒
Well, use your best judgment, I mean 60 times a second?
这就会push主队列
That's going to be pushing the main queue.
10次每秒 没问题
Ten times a second, no problem.
取决于你在block中做什么
It depends on what you're doing in that block.
但愿你没有做代价很高的图像运算
Hopefully you're not doing some very, very expensive graphics operation.
不过 你可以把这设为主队列
But you could make that the main queue.
你也可以把这设为别的队列
Or you could make that be some other queue.
然后合并事件 然后派回到
And then coalesce events, and then just dispatch back
主队列 来进行UI更新
to the main queue whenever you want to do the UI updating.
这个block的调用有多频繁呢
So how often does this block get called?
顺便提下 这是设备运动的那些
This is the device motion ones, by the way.
设备运动知道很多信息 它还可以有
Device Motion knows so much information it can actually have
一个关于z轴和xy轴在哪的参考系
a reference frame about where's Z axis and X and Y axis,
你也可以自己去查这些
and all that, so you can look that up as well.
不过这里方式还是一样的 放一个block在队列上
But it's the same way, though, in terms of you just put a block on the queue
设备运动产生变化时 它就会告诉你
and when device motion has changes, it's going to tell you.
所有这些情形下
So in all these cases,
你都要设置block被调用的时间区间
you set the interval at which it's going to call your block
使用这个UpdateInterval属性
using this update interval property.
这个可以用于加速计 陀螺仪
So whether you're doing accelerometer, gyro,
磁力计和设备运动 你只需要设置时间区间
magnetometer, device motion, you just set the interval.
以秒计算 如果你希望是10次每秒
This is in seconds, so if you want it 10 times a second,
这里就可以设为0.1 如果你想20次每秒 那就是0.05
you would say 0.1, if you want 20 times a second, 0.05.
这些东西可以有多频繁呢
How often can these things go?
这里有限制
There are limits.
这些东西无法一秒钟汇报一千次
These things can't report thousand times a second,
一秒钟一千次你可能也做不了什么
probably you couldn't do much with 1,000 times a second,
你在UI中无法作出反应
you couldn't respond in the UI or anything to that.
我想 这些东西只能到60赫兹
I think most of these things are around 60 Hz.
60次每秒或许就是这里的极限了
60 times a second, probably about the maximum you're going to get out of them.
说明文档中可能没有专门说
I don't think the documentation specifically says.
这里可以有多个处理器block
It is okay to have multiple handler blocks.
也就是说 你可以调用startAccelerometerUpdates
In other words, to call start accelerometer updates
带block 给它一个block
with block, give it a block,
之后再在别处
and then later somewhere else,
startAccelerometerUpdates 带block
start accelerator updates with block
再给另外一个block
and give it a different block,
两个block都会被调用
and both of those blocks will get called.
调用频率也相同
They're both going to get called at the same rate,
这个更新时间区间
this update interval, but two different--
但每个时间区间内 你可以做两件不同的事
you could be doing two different things every time this interval happens.
这完全没问题 这里并不只能处理一个block
That's perfectly fine, say it's not like there can only be one block.
理解吗
Make sense?
好 我有一个demo
Alright, so I have a demo.
这个最好是用demo来讲更好理解
This is all definitely best understood with a demo,
demo中我还会演示其它一些东西
and this demo lets me show you a couple other things as well,
同往常一样 我的demo都是一举多得的
as usual, I try to make these demos count for multiple things here,
这是一个新app 叫作Bouncer
so this is going to be a new app we're going to write, it's called Bouncer.
Bouncer将有一个小方块
And Bouncer is going to be a little square that I'm going
出现在屏幕上
to have appear on my device,
最终我们会让重力来决定
and eventually we're going to have gravity
方块在屏幕上动画到什么地方去
determine where that square is animated to on screen,
然后我们会加一个方块
then we'll put another square on there, and then
让两者相互碰撞
we'll bang those things into each other,
我们还会计分
and maybe we'll put a little score in there,
然后再写个小游戏
and then we've made ourselves a little game.
这是一个小游戏
So it's a little, basically
游戏的输入是加速计
game where the input to the game is the accelerometer.
我将用加速计
So I'm going to use accelerometer,
因为这是设备运动中最简单的
because it's the simplest of the device motion things.
不过获得信息的方式都是一样的
But they all basically do the same approach of how you get the information back.
我们将使用加速计来驱动我们的UI
So we use the accelerometer to drive our UI, just like
像是接触 猛击这些
touching and swiping, or whatever,
我们将把加速计当作输入
we're going to use the accelerometer as an input.
好 这里创建一个新项目
Alright, so let's make a new project here.
不是新文件
Whoops! Not a new file.
取消 新项目
Cancel. A new project.
好 这个项目起名为Bouncer
Okay. And we're going to call this project Bouncer.
它将是通用的
And it's going to be universal.
这个app中将有一点是之前我从未做过的
I'm also going to do something with this app that I haven't done all quarter,
也就是 我不会在故事板中做任何事
which is I'm not going to do anything in the storyboard.
这里100%是用代码
We're going to do all of this 100 percent in code,
看看这是怎样的
just to see what that looks like.
我不打算接触故事板
So I'm not even going to touch my storyboard.
实际上 我打算把故事板移到支持文件中
Alright, in fact, I'm going to move my storyboards down to supporting files,
因为我不打算用
because I'm not going to use them. It's all going to be
整个实现都在这一个文件中
in this one file, the entire implementation we're going to do here.
好 首先我们要做什么呢
Alright, so what are we going to do to start?
首先将一个红色方块放到屏幕上
Let's start by just putting a little red square on the screen.
这很简单
So we'll start simple.
这里我写一个属性 非原子
I'm going to have a little property here, non-atomic,
强 只是一个小UIView 起名为redBlock
strong, just a little UI view, I'm going to call it red block.
这是我将放到屏幕上的一个红色小方块
It's going to be a little red square that I'm going to put on screen.
我将在viewDidAppear中将它放到屏幕上
And I'm going to do it, I'm going to put in on screen in ViewDidAppear,
一旦这个视图出现在屏幕上
so once this view appears on screen,
我马上就会把这个小方块放上去
then I'm going to put this little block out there,
做法是通过这个方法 startGame
and I'm going to do that in a method called Start Game,
该方法会开始游戏
so it's going to be the start of my game.
最终 这里将不只是一个红色方块
I mean, eventually it's going to be more than just a red block there,
因此 这里我们说startGame
so we'll say we're starting our game.
startGame中怎么做呢
So what do we do in Start Game?
我只打算说 self.redBlock = …
I'm just going to say self dot red block equals--
我需要创建一个方块 我想把它放到屏幕中央
now I would need to create a block, I want to put it in the center of the screen,
因此 在这里 我会创建一个方法 叫addBlock…
so I create a nice little method here, called add block,
如这里所示 它的作用很明显
this little guy right here, and all it does, as you can see,
也就是initWithFrame和addSubview
is it just does init with frame and add subview.
它会计算frame在哪
And all it's doing is calculating where that frame is.
它会放到中央 偏移我想要的值 任何UI偏移量
So it's putting in the center offset by anything I want, any UI offset.
最开始 我将把方块放到中央
So I'm going to put it initially right in the center.
顺便说下 这个和这个在整个demo中不会用到
By the way, we don't need this or this for this entire demo.
然后我说self addBlockOffset…
Alright, so I'm going to do self, add, block, offset,
然后是UIOffsetMake 0 0
and I'm going to do UI offset make zero zero.
这就放到了中央
So it's going to put it right in the center.
大家都理解这个的作用了吗
Everyone understand what this does,
它将一个UIView放到了屏幕中央
is just putting-- adding UI view to the center of the screen.
我的方块是红色的 因此这里用红色
And my block is red, so let's make it red.
.backgroundColor = UIColor redColor
Dot background color equals UI color, red color.
让我们来运行这个
So let's go ahead and run that.
好 很好的开始
Alright, good start.
下面 我希望有一些重力
So what we want now is I want some gravity.
我希望这个方块不再待在中央 而是移动到别处
I want this block to go somewhere else besides in the middle of the screen.
做法你们已经非常熟悉了
So we do that with something you're all very familiar
这是作业四的内容 也就是动态动画器
from assignment 4, which is animators, dynamic animator.
这里我将添加一个动态动画器
So I'm just going to add a dynamic animator here
来加入重力
to add gravity
让方块来到边缘时
and to make it so when the block gets to the edge,
会反弹
it's going to bounce off.
而不是离开屏幕
Instead of just going off the screen.
让我们来做这个
So let's do that.
你们都知道动画器
Uh, that, I have since you all know about animator,
我就不一点点键入了
I'm not going to type all that in, I'm just going
直接把它们加到这里
to show it here, this is what I just added.
这里
Right here.
我有一些属性
Okay, I've got some properties.
这里的属性是
The properties I have here are...
一个动态动画器 还有重力行为
a dynamic animator, of course, I've got a gravity behavior,
这是拉拽红色方块的重力
that's going to be the gravity pulling on my red block.
碰撞器 这是外边缘处的情况
Collider, that's just going to be the outer edges,
这是现在唯一的碰撞器
that's the only collider I'm going to have for now.
然后弹性是一个项目行为
And then elastic is an item behavior.
我希望它碰壁弹回
I want it to really bounce off the walls.
这里我设置了它的弹性 让它具有完全弹性
So I'm going to set it's elasticity so that it's completely elastic.
碰壁都是弹性碰撞
All of it's hitting the walls are elastic collisions.
这是动画器
And so here's the animator.
惰性实例化 没有特别的东西 这是碰撞器
Lazy instantiation not doing anything special there, here's the collider.
其作用是translatesReferenceBoundsIntoBoundary
The only thing that does is translates reference bounds into boundary.
你们知道这个
Okay, you know about that.
这是重力 不过是默认的重力
Here's gravity, just default gravity.
一开始重力会在视图中指向下方
It's going to start out with our gravity pointing down in our view.
而无论下是哪个方向 换句话说
Whatever down is in our view, in other words,
视图Y方向向下 这就是重力最开始的情况
increasing Y, that's where gravity's going to start out,
我们希望用现实世界的重力取代这个重力
we want to replace that gravity with the real gravity of the world,
这是我们马上要做的
that's what we're going to be doing in a moment.
然后这里是弹性
And then here's elastic.
弹性也就是项目行为中的弹性
Elastic is an item behavior which just sets one thing, which is the elasticity.
说的是碰撞弹性有多强
This says how elastic the collisions are, and I'm going
我设为1.0 也就是完全弹性碰撞
to have it be 1.0, which means fully elastic collision.
你甚至可以将这个设为大于1
You can actually make this greater than 1, and it will pick
这样碰撞时就会加速
up speed when it hits a collision,
你也可以设为小于1 这时就会有阻尼
and you can make it less than 1, and it will dampen, right?
最小值是0 这好像是默认值
All the way down to zero, which is the default, I think,
也就是方块碰到底部
which is that's a block, hit the bottom
就不再弹起
and then just kind of settle real quick.
这就是程序中方块的弹性了
That's what we had, I think, the elasticity of our blocks in Drop It, were that.
好 我有了动画器和所有这些
Alright, so I have this animator and all these things,
下面我要将红色方块添加到这些
so now I just want to make sure that I take my red block and add it to all these,
我这里说 我希望红色方块在碰撞器中
so I'm going to say I want the red block to be in the collider,
我希望红色方块具有弹性
and I want the red block to be elastic.
我希望红色方块受重力影响
And I want the red block to be affected by gravity.
我把红色方块加到了这些行为
Okay, so I'm just adding the red block to these behaviors.
但愿这些你们都很熟悉 这是作业四的内容
Again, hopefully this is all really familiar to you from assignment 4.
看看我们现在有些什么
So let's run to see what we've got now.
我们有了重力 碰撞和弹性
So we've got gravity, collision and elastic,
于是这个红色方块就会下落弹起
so this red block, boom, it goes down and it bounces.
这很棒 我们开了个好头
So this is excellent, we've got a good start here.
很不幸的是 这还不是现实世界的重力
Unfortunately, this is not real-world gravity,
转动设备
I'm moving this thing around,
它还是在这个方向上弹
it's still going straight down and bouncing.
因为默认重力是视图中的Y方向向下
That's because the default gravity is down, in other words increasing Y in my view.
下面我将使用运动管理器
So what I'm going to do now is use the motion manager
将重力从Y方向向下
to set the gravity to instead of being down,
设为实际重力 使用加速计
to be wherever the real gravity is, by using the accelerometer.
记得吧 加速计测量的总是重力加速度
Okay, remember, the accelerometer is always measuring acceleration due
这样我就总能知道实际重力在哪
to gravity so I will always know where real gravity is.
让我们来做这个
So let's do that.
这也很简单 我们在startGame中来做这个
That's pretty straightforward too, we're going to do that here in Start Game.
做Core Motion的任何事情 都需要一个运动管理器
So to do anything with core motion, I need a motion manager.
到这里获得一个运动管理器
So let's go get a motion manager here.
设置一个属性 非原子 强
I'm going to make a property, non-atomic strong,
CMMotionManager 我需要导入
CMMotionManager, okay I need to import.
Core Motion
Core motion.
哦 不是Core Media
Oops, not core media,
Core Motion
core motion.
好 现在我就有了一个运动管理器
Alright. And now I have a motion manager,
我将惰性实例化这个东西
and I'm going to lazily instantiate this thing.
让我们在下面这里来做
So let's do that down here.
CMMotionManager
CMMotionManager,
if (!_motionManager)
if not motion manager,
那么_motionManager =
then motion manager equals
CMMotionManager alloc init
CMMotionManager alloc init,
然后我这样设置运动管理器
and then I'm going to set the motion manager
让它进行加速计更新 频率10次每秒
to do accelerometer updates at 10 per second.
应该够了
Should be enough.
我是说 这里对于UI
I mean, I'm doing UI here.
我觉得10次每秒就足够让红色方块
I think 10 per second is going to give me smooth enough changing of direction,
在运动中获得平滑的方向变化了
of my red square as I move around, but you know,
不过如果反应不够快 我可以调高一些
I could crank it up a little bit if it doesn't seem responsive enough to my moving,
如果反应太快 我也可以调低一些
or I could crank it down if it seems plenty responsive
这样就能避免绘制的内容多于需要绘制的内容
and I just don't want to do any more drawing than I have to do.
这里先设为这个
So we're going to set it to be that,
然后返回我们的运动管理器
and then let's return our motion manager.
现在我有了这个运动管理器
Okay, so now we have this motion manager, so now what I'm going
然后我要检查
to do is say first of all I'm going to check to see
我是否已经在进行加速计更新
if I'm already doing accelerometer updates,
这里我说 isAccelerometerActive
so I'm going to say accelerometer active.
我只在加速计没有在活动时
And I'm only going to start monitoring this thing
才开始监视这个东西
if the accelerometer is not already active.
哦 让我删掉这个 谢谢
Whoops, let me...erase...thank you...okay.
如果没在活动 那我就会
So if it's not active, then I'm going
给它一个block来调用
to basically give it a block to call me,
而block的作用是更新重力行为的重力
and all I'm going to do in that block is update my gravity behavior's gravity.
让我们来做这个
So let's do that.
self.motionManager
Self dot motion manager,
startAccelerometerUpdatesToQueue
start accelerometer updates to queue,
我将给它一个队列 每秒仅仅10次
so we'll give it a queue, I'm only doing 10 per second,
我想主队列处理得来
I think I can easily go main queue on this one.
因此这里设为主队列
So I'll go main queue,
这里是处理器
and here's the handler.
双击得到处理器
Double clicking to get the handler,
放到这里来 这样更容易看清
we'll put this right here, in fact, we'll make it even easier
把这里移回去 像这样
to see, we'll move this back here like this.
好 这是处理器
Alright. So here's our handler.
在处理器中我们要做什么呢
And what do we want to do inside this handler?
我们要获得加速度的x和y
Well let's get the X and Y of acceleration,
让我们获得x 这是accelerometerData
so let's get the X, that's accelerometer data.
也就是方块的这个参数
So that's this argument here to our block,
.acceleration
dot acceleration,
这就是现有的加速度
that's the acceleration that is happening,
而x是我要的方向
and X is the direction I want.
这是x方向
So here's the X direction, and then I'm going
y也一样 y = accelerometerData.acceleration.y
to do the same thing Y equals accelerometer data, acceleration, dot Y.
这样我就有了x和y方向上由于重力产生的加速度
So now I have the X and Y acceleration due to gravity.
还有设备的运动
And do the device moving.
两者都
Both.
这是一个组合
So it's a kind of combination.
如果我将设备向下倾斜 方块就会往下
So that way, if I tilt my thing down, my blocks are going to go down.
如果反过来倾斜 方块也会反过来
If I tilt it back the other way, it's going to go the other way, right?
如果我摇动它 它就会朝那个方向加速
If I shake it over, it's going to accelerate a little bit in that direction.
这里方块对设备加速有些响应
So it's kind of like that block is going to be responding
不过主要是基于重力的加速度
to my acceleration and my device, but mostly acceleration due to gravity.
我如何设置这个行为的重力方向呢
So how do I set the direction of the gravity of that behavior?
我有self.gravity 这是我的重力行为
Well, I have self dot gravity, that's my gravity behavior.
它有gravityDirection 重力方向
It has something called gravity direction, which is exactly what we want.
这是一个向量 一个CGVector
It's a vector, a CG vector,
它有一个Δx和一个Δy
and it just has a delta X and delta Y vector, right?
同数学中的向量一样 我们有这个向量
So like in math, vector, and so we're just going to have the vector,
让我们尝试x和y 看会发生什么
let's try doing X and Y, see what happens here.
它无法正常工作 不过不妨一试
It's not going to work, but we'll try it.
然后是分号
And we can do semicolon.
有些人应该已经开始想这为什么不行了
Okay. Now, hopefully in some of your minds you're trying
毕竟这看起来似乎应该能行才对
to think why this is not going to work, because it seems like this should just work.
我们看看会发生什么
But let's see what happens.
有人猜猜为什么不能正常工作吗 请讲
Anyone want to hazard a guess why it's not going to work? Yeah?
对 回答是
Yeah, so the answer that was posited is
纵轴可以翻转 说得没错
that the vertical axis can be flipped, and that's true.
或许更好的说法是
Maybe a better way of saying it is that the acceleration
这个设备的加速度总是
of this device is always the acceleration
在设备中朝这个方向往下
where it's...down this way in the device,
如果我把它横过来
so if I have it turned sideways, okay,
注意方块在弹
then look at my thing it's bouncing.
把这个拿起来 它却朝这个方向弹
I have this turned up, face-up, and it's bouncing this way.
为什么这样弹呢
Why is it bouncing this way?
因为它是在这个轴上进行测量
That's because it's measuring this stuff all on this axis.
我想让它在这个轴上测量 这里是z
I want it measuring it in this axis, basically, where here's Z,
这里是y 这里是x
here's Y, and here's X.
因此我需要知道 用户将设备朝向哪个方向
So I basically have to know which way the user has my device turned.
这里我把它放成横屏模式
So I have it turned kind of landscape.
横屏左 home键在左边
Landscape left, the home button is on the left.
我需要翻转x和y
So that's going to-- I'm going to have to flip the X and Y
去-y而不是y
and go negative Y instead of Y,
如果是这个方向
and if I were doing it this way,
这里我锁了
which I have my...locked in here.
如果我反过来 它就会翻转
But if I do it the other way around, then it's flipped.
这是另一个方向 如果这样向上 它会是另一个方向
It has to be the other way, and if I'm doing it up this way, then it's another way.
重力加速度怎样影响我的视图取决于
So basically, which way the acceleration to gravity is affecting my view depends
视图的朝向是怎样的
on what the orientation of my view is.
我们加些代码来处理这个
So let's put some code in to deal with that.
其实很简单
Turns out to be pretty straightforward.
我们不能这么头脑简单
So we can't just do this simple one.
将这个删掉
So let's take that out.
为了节省键入工作量 我这样
And...to save some typing, we'll do it this way.
所有视图控制器都有这个属性
So all view controllers have this property called
self.interfaceOrientation
self interface orientation that will
告诉你是竖屏还是横屏
tell you whether you're portrait, portrait upside-down,
是正的还是反的
landscape left or landscape right.
这是视图控制器告诉你 你还可以从设备得到
That's telling you, the view controller, you can also get this from the device.
还有一个很有趣 你可以从UIApplication得到
And you can also get an interesting one from UI application,
或许在这里使用会更好 也就是statusBarOrientation
might even be better to use here, which is status bar orientation.
这告诉你状态栏在哪
That tells you where the status bar is.
或许这是最正确的东西
And that's really probably the most correct thing,
或许也是这里我们应当用的
and probably what we should be using here.
因为在用户看来
Because from the user's standpoint,
状态栏在哪 哪就应该是屏幕顶部
wherever their status bar is, that's the top of the screen.
哪怕是像这样旋转 它处在错误的位置
Even if it's been slow to notice rotation, and it's in the wrong place,
对于用户而言
to the user, it's still to them,
用户仍然认为这是屏幕顶部
they think that's the top of their screen.
不过这里只需要跟踪就行了
But this is mostly going to track that anyway,
我们用这个 这个更方便
so we'll use this one, it's convenient.
这里 横屏右
And so here, landscape right,
可以看到 x和y交换了位置
you can see we are swapping the X and Y. You see?
这是x 我用的是y
This is the X, and I'm using the Y. Alright?
在横屏中我们都这样做了
And so both of the landscapes we're doing that in,
y是负是正则依赖于
and whether Y is negative or positive depends, you know,
横屏模式是反过来的 还是正确方向向上
Y increases as we go down, so it just depends
on whether we're portrait upside down or portrait right side up,
竖屏模式也一样
and same thing for landscape.
你们可以以后再来研究这个
So you can look at these, stare at these later,
确信这是正确的x和y
as in convince yourself these are the right Xs and Ys.
这里我们用的是不同的 具体要看情况
But you can just see, that we're using different ones depending.
我们看看这个怎么样
So let's see how this works.
找到一个很好的朝向
Let's get ourselves into a nice orientation here.
这里
Just, here.
现在是往下弹 然后我转动设备
Alright, so now it's bouncing around, and if I tilt it, see,
它弹到了一侧 再转向另一侧
it's going off to the side, or I tilt it to the other side,
或是转向这边 或是往下
or tilt it this way or down.
它现在跟着我转动设备在运动
So now it's following me, however I tilt my device,
它追随着重力 我还可以用它来
it is following that gravity, and I can kind of use it
越来越快地加速 看到了吗
to accelerate faster and faster even, see that?
这就是我想要的
So this is exactly what I want.
现在我就能够控制红色方块运动到哪
I've got this thing so that I can control where my red block goes,
运动取决于我倾斜设备的方式
depending on how I tilt my device.
我锁定了我的用户界面朝向
Okay, now I've locked my user interface orientation here.
看 如果解锁 它就会有些让人不知所措
Watch, if I unlock it, then it's a little disconcerting
我点这里 转向 哦
because okay I'm clicking here, now I turn, and whoop!
我的状态栏移动了 但还是能行
My status bar moved, but it's still working.
因为每次获得更新时
Because every time I get an update,
它还是会重新调整下方在哪
it's still readjusting to where down is.
用户可能有些晕头转向
It's a little disconcerting to the user.
如果我是用户 我在玩这个游戏
If I were a user and really playing this game,
我或许就应该锁定设备的朝向
I would probably, you know, lock my thing into some orientation,
开关在这里 像这样
where's that switch, here it is, like this.
这样玩起来就更有趣一些
It would just be a little more fun to play this game
我的状态栏不会到处转 不过这还是能工作
if it wasn't constantly switching my status bar, but it's still working,
只是这样会更好一些
it's just a little...okay, this is better.
之前讲的都理解吗 有问题
Make sense what we're doing so far? Question?
问题是 编程上能否锁定屏幕旋转
The question is can you programmatically do rotation lock?
理论上可以 因为你可以指定说 应用程序只在
Well, you kind of can, because you can specify that you're application only works
特定朝向下能够工作
in certain orientations, right?
这样实际上就将朝向锁定住了
And so by doing so, then you can basically do orientation lock.
我不知道有没有做法可以说
So. I don't know that there's a way to kind of say
锁定在当前朝向
"lock it in the current orientation,"
我不确定 也有可能有
like I'm not sure there's a way to do that, there might be,
不过我不知道
but I don't know offhand.
这样我们就能让方块弹起 并对我们的行为作出反应
Alright. So now we've got this thing bouncing and responding
这很棒
to our thing, that's a good idea.
下面我将
One thing I'm going to do also here is I'm going
在开始之前将重力方向设为
to set the gravity direction before we start,
VectorMake(0,0)
equal to vector makes zero, zero.
这是因为在开始之前
That's because I'm going to be starting this thing going off.
我不想让第一个有任何的向下加速度
I don't want, before the first one goes off, to have any kind of downward acceleration,
我这里设置成为没有重力
so I'm basically going to set it so we have no gravity, and then
然后开启加速计 让这个开始运动
I'm going to start this accelerometer to get the, this going.
这很好
So that's good.
如果再加一个方块就会更酷了
Alright. This would be kind of cool if we added another block.
这里让我再来创建一个黑色方块
So let's put another block in here. I'm going to create a black block.
到上面这里 设置属性 非原子
So I'm going to go up here, and set property, non-atomic,
或许这些应该设为弱
actually might as well make these weak,
如果它们离开了视图层级
if they leave the view hierarchy,
我们就应该把它们清除掉
then we'll clean them up.
黑色方块
Black block.
注意 这里的所有行为也都设为了弱
Notice I made these behaviors all weak as well.
为什么设为弱呢
Why did I make these weak?
因为 如果这个动态动画器没有
Well, because if this dynamic animator isn't holding
强引用它们 那我就不想要它们了
on strongly to them, then I don't want them.
outlet设为弱也是一样的道理
Same thing when we make an outlet weak, right?
如果视图层级不再引用它们
If the view hierarchy isn't holding on to them,
这里我没有使用故事板
and since I'm not doing storyboards here,
我只是写代码 不过情况还是一样
I'm doing code, I'm still kind of doing the same thing.
如果不再处在视图层级中
I don't want my red and black block to be around
我显然就不再需要红色和黑色方块
if I take them out of the view hierarchy.
下面来创建黑色方块
Alright, so let's make my black block.
很类似
Actually it's very similar.
我们可以从红色方块那里复制粘贴
Let's copy and paste my red block,
黑色方块 我们这样做
black block, and we'll do this, and...
很有趣
Well that's interesting.
这很奇怪
Okay. That's very strange.
好 黑色方块 这里也是黑色方块
Okay, black block, and then here's another black block,
黑色方块需要是黑色的
and the black block wants to be black,
我们希望黑色方块有碰撞器的作用
and we're going to have the black block do the collider,
但它不是弹性的 也不考虑重力这些
but I'm not going to have it be as elastic, nor am I going to have it do the gravity.
黑色方块唯一运动的情况
So the black block, the only thing that's going to make the black block move
是跟红色方块碰撞时
is if we hit it with the red block. That's the only thing that can impart.
或是同边缘碰撞时
Or if it collides with the edge, we'll get a little bit
我们会得到一些反应
of reactive thing, but that's basically it.
这是黑色
This is black.
让我们把黑色方块放到这里
Alright? So let's put that black block on there,
两者一开始不能都在中间
and let's not have them both start in the center,
这个开始于-100 这个开始于+100
so we'll have that one start at minus 100 and this one start at plus 100.
看看是怎样的
So we'll see what this looks like.
红色方块之外 加了一个黑色方块
You add a black block to our red block.
可以看到 碰撞它 两者都会弹开
Okay. So now if I can hit it, see you can see that they're both bouncing around.
红色这个有弹性
The red one has more elasticity,
它会比黑色方块弹得更远
so it bounces off quite a bit more powerfully than the black block.
不过我还是可以让黑色方块运动
But I can still try and get that black block moving.
你可以很快将这做成一个游戏
So now you can imagine turning this into a game pretty quick,
游戏的目标是保持黑色方块的运动
which is the object of the game is to keep that black block moving.
运动维持得越好 你的得分就会越高
The more you can make that black block move, the more points you get.
我们给这个游戏添加一个分数
So let's go add some score. Let's add a score to this game.
这部分不能算是学习练习
Now this part is not really that much of a learning exercise,
我只打算快速键入 你们可以以后去看
so I'm going to just type that in, real fast, you can go look at this later.
涉及到很多属性
It's got a whole bunch of properties involved
用来计分 像这样
in keeping score, like that,
我们在代码中 只需要更新分数
and all we need to do in our code is update the score.
我打算按加速计的频率更新计分
And I'm going to update my score when the accelerometer goes off.
也就是10次每秒 这个频率似乎不错
That's 10 times a second, that seems like a good rate to me,
我打算这样更新分值
so I'm just going to update my score there.
我们来看看这个
So let's look at that.
积分只是跟踪黑色方块在哪
All the scorekeeping does is just keeps track of where the black block is,
它这样做了多久
how long it's been doing that,
然后分数被写到中间
and then it puts the score in the middle there. You can see,
这里同时记录了当前分数和目前最高分
and it keeps both the current score and your highest score so far, with this block.
如果你让黑色方块停下 不再撞击它
If you let the black block stay there, and you don't hit it,
可以看到 分值很快就会降低
you can see that my score is going to start going down pretty soon.
看到了吧 正在下降
See, it's going down.
再次撞击它 它又会开始运动
But if I start hitting it again, make it move there we go,
分数又会上升
it will start going back up again.
这样做得越久 分值就越难上升
And the longer I keep doing this, the harder it is to get my score high,
现在还好
but it's doing okay.
你们可以试试最高能得多少分
So you can try and see what's the highest possible score.
我没有很好地完成保持黑色方块移动的任务
Now I haven't done a very good job here of keeping that black block moving,
可以想象 分数还可以比这高很多
so you can imagine the scores could be much, much higher.
还注意一点很有趣 碰到分数时 方块也会弹开
Notice also for fun, I made it so that the score bounces off.
无法穿越分数
So it doesn't go over the scores.
这会让游戏更难一些
This will just kind of make it a little harder, actually,
你无法直接击中方块
so you can't go straight to that block, you have to
你需要绕过分数的障碍
think about the score being in the way.
这很酷
So that's kind of cool.
我们准备把这发布到App商店
We're almost ready to ship this on the app store.
还需要做什么呢
What else are we going to do?
我们来想想这类游戏的一个很重要的部分
Let's go ahead and think about an important part of a game like this,
也就是暂停
which is pausing.
为什么要暂停呢
Why would you ever want to pause this game?
原因有很多
A lot of reasons.
这个游戏可能处在一系列游戏中 有一个标签栏
What if this game were in a suite of games, where there was a tab bar,
你可以在游戏间切换
and you were switching between games.
点击其它选项卡切换到别的游戏
When you switch to another game on a different tab,
例如Machismo 这个游戏就需要暂停
like machismo or something, you would want this game to pause,
以后回到它时 它就应当继续
and then when you went back to it, you would want to continue.
我也有可能切换到另外一个程序
Or what if I switch to another app?
像这样 切换到另一个程序
I go like this, and go switch to another app
做点别的什么 然后回到游戏发现 哦
and doing some other things, you know, and then I come back to my game, it's like, "Oh!
我的分数毁了
My score! Ruined."
因为方块一直待在那里没动
Because it was sitting there doing nothing for all that time.
我希望这里有暂停 回来时再继续
I want it to pause, and then continue when I come back.
我也有可能需要点击屏幕时暂停
Or maybe I want to be able to just tap on it and pause,
再点击继续
and tap again to continue, right?
暂停/继续是很需要的
So pausing/resuming would be really cool.
那如何让游戏暂停/继续呢
So how can we make our game pause and resume?
我们可以很轻松地将startGame转化为
Well, we can take this start game and turn it pretty easily
resumeGame
into resume game,
我们只需要检查
and all we need to do to do that is check
游戏是否已经开始
to see if the game is already started,
如果已经开始… 这里应该是非
because if it's already started, well that's going to be not,
if (!…redBlock)
if not red block,
如果游戏没开始 我们就需要创建红色和黑色方块
if we haven't start a game, then we need to create the red and black block.
否则 我们可以开启这个加速计
But otherwise, we can just fire up this accelerometer,
暂停则只需要停止加速计
and what we'll do to pause is we'll just stop the accelerometer.
这里我只需要说
So I'm just going to say
self.motionManager stopAccelerometerUpdates
self dot motion manager stop accelerometer updates.
我这就暂停了 停止了加速计的更新
So I've paused, I've just stopped the accelerometer from updating.
这很好
Which is a pretty good thing.
然后还要暂停计分 我显然要这样做
I also have pause scoring okay, because I want to do that.
不要太在意这个里面都有些什么
Don't look too closely behind the curtain for that one
我还希望我的重力方向回到0
and then also I want my gravity direction to be back to being zero.
暂停时 我不希望红色方块还因重力运动
I don't want my red thing to be trying to do gravity when it's paused, right?
这就是暂停游戏所需要做的
So that's all I really need to do to pause this game.
让我们添加一个点击手势用于暂停和继续游戏
So let's put a little tap gesture in that pauses the game, and then continues the game.
这个这时可以继续
This will, now can be resume,
我要创建一个点击手势 在viewDidLoad中
and so I'm going to do a tap gesture, I'm going to do it in ViewDidLoad.
我说过 我不打算在故事板中做任何事
Told you I wasn't going to do anything in the storyboard, and so I'm just going
这里我说 self.view addGestureRecognizer
to say self dot view add gesture recognizer,
UITapGesture…
UI tap gesture,
alloc
initWithTarget:self
init with target self,
action是tap 就这些了
action is going to be tap, okay, that's it.
这样我就添加了点击手势 然后创建tap
So now I've added this tap gesture, so now let's make tap.
tap的作用是这样的
And all tap needs to do is when you say
如果暂停了 那就继续
if we're paused, then resume,
否则就暂停
otherwise, pause.
我们需要isPaused 如何知道有没有暂停呢
So we need an "is paused," how are we going to tell if we're paused or not?
很简单 isPaused 我将返回
Real easy, is paused, I'm just going to return
如果运动管理器的加速计没有处在活动状态
if the motion manager's accelerometer is not active.
So if the accelerometer in the motion manager is not active,
那么我们就要暂停
then we must be paused.
明白吗
See what I did there?
我们来试试这个
So let's go try this, see if this works.
这个将能行
And this is going to work,
不过同我们想要的可能会有出入 我们来看看
but not quite exactly how we might want, as you'll see.
首先让这个开始运动
Alright, so let's go get some motion happening here first.
这个现在在运动 我点暂停
Alright, so we got this thing, motion, I'm going to hit pause.
暂停了 但还在动
Okay, so it paused, okay, but it's still--
暂停时加速计不再工作
it paused in that my accelerometer is not working,
但红色方块还在运动
but the red block still kind of kept moving,
这里我重新开启 重力回来了 暂停
so here I turn it back on, gravity's back, I pause,
红色方块还会运动好久
it's like the red block keeps moving a long way.
为什么它还在运动呢
Okay, why does that red block keep moving?
因为之前有一个力施加在它之上
Well, because it already has a force applied to it,
现在它要让这个力的作用自己消失
and it's just letting that force kind of play out.
真正的暂停
So what would be really nice when we pause is
最好是在这里放些减速沙 让其快速减慢
if we put some quicksand in here, and everything kind of slowed down, right?
我不希望一切立刻停止
I don't want everything to stop immediately,
不过我希望它们能够很好地减速
but I want things to, you know, nicely slow down.
如何添加减速沙呢
So how do we add quicksand?
这可以通过另一个动态动画器的做法来做到
Well, I can do that with another dynamic animator thing.
放到下面这里
Let's put this down here,
这里我将它称作quicksand
I'm going to call it quicksand, in fact, alright?
quicksand是这里我要加的另一个行为
And so quicksand is just another behavior that I'm adding right here.
quicksand是怎样的呢
And what does this quicksand look like?
它是这样的 这就是我加的
It's this, it's what I added.
这是一个具有阻力的UIDynamicAnimator
And as a UI dynamic animator that has resistance,
阻力是物体上对抗所施力的阻力
so resistance is a item's resistance to forces being applied to it.
最开始这是0 因此阻力是0 这是默认值
So I'll start it out at zero, which means no resistance to it. That's the default.
它不会阻碍任何的力 包括重力
So it doesn't resist any of the forces, you know, the gravity,
这些都不受阻 方块到处弹
it doesn't resist any of that, just things are bouncing around.
然后在暂停时 我会让这个阻力瞬间提高到1
And then when we pause, I'm going to crank this resistance up to like at least 1.
1也就是完全抵抗所施力 让速度很快下降
1 is it completely resists forces so it will slow down really quickly,
这个值还可以大于1
but I can go even more than 1,
也就是积极降低所施力 反应会非常积极
which is it actively, you know, reduces its forces on it, its response to forces on it.
总之 我们有了quicksand
But we've got this quicksand,
我们只需要将两个物体 红色方块
all we need to do is add both the red item, the red block,
还有黑色方块 添加到quicksand
and the black block, to the quicksand.
我少复制了一次
I missed a copy key quite a bit.
好 黑色方块
Okay black block.
把它们都放到quicksand中
So we'll put them both in this quicksand,
然后我们要在暂停时
and then we're just going to, when we pause,
将quicksand的阻力设为
we're going to set the quicksand's resistance
10 这是非常高的阻力
to let's say 10, which is pretty high resistance,
物体会很快慢下来
they're going to slow down pretty fast with that.
如果实在太大 我们还可以调整
We could tweak that, whether we want it to be that much.
之后继续游戏时
And then when we resume the game,
我们会将quicksand的阻力重新设为0
we're going to set the quicksand's resistance back to zero.
让我们来做这个
So let's do that.
做这个是为了让你们看到暂停的效果
And I'm mostly doing this so you can see the effect of pausing,
因为后面我还会讲到另一种情况下的暂停
because next we're going to show how to do pausing in a different circumstance.
这里 让这个开始动 它在到处运动
Okay so here, let's go, get this guy going again, right, he's moving around.
点暂停 看它停得有多快
Now, if I pause, let's see how quickly he stopped.
还在旋转 但运动已经停止了
He's still spinning, but he has stopped his motion.
如果继续 重力就会重新作用于它
And if I continue, now gravity is going to work on him again.
像这样快速停止 让你有了作弊的机会
One thing about stopping him so quickly, it allows you to cheat a little bit,
操作不好控制时
because if this guy's out of control
你可以通过暂停来重新获得控制
and you're trying to get him back in control so you can get
停下来以后再重开 你就很容易追上黑色方块了
after the black block, this stops him, right? Too quick.
因此 或许10作为阻力值有些太大
So it might be that having 10 be our quicksand is a little too high.
或许1就够了
Maybe we only want 1.
这时减缓的速度就会更正常 更慢
Which would mean it would slow down kind of at a normal or a much slower rate.
你们可以自己调
So you could play with that.
什么时候我们想暂停呢
Alright, so when would we want to do pausing.
需要暂停的一个很重要的地方就是
Well, one of the real important places to pause is
用户点击进入另一个程序
when someone clicks to go to another app.
我打算简要回到幻灯片
So I'm going to go back to the slides, really briefly,
跟你们讲这个
and show you this,
然后 我们再回来
and then we'll go back.
你的程序的状态 你的程序的生命周期
So your applications state the life cycle of your application,
会通过特定状态
it goes through certain states,
其中之一就是 它是活动的应用程序
and one of them is it's the active application.
活动应用程序是说你在获取事件
And being the active application means you're getting events,
你的视图在获取事件
your views are getting events, right?
触摸事件在发生
Touch events are happening to you.
你在对世界作出响应
You're basically responding to the world.
这些都只发生在你是活动程序的时候
That's only happens when you're the active application.
如果你是活动程序 你的方块在弹动
Now, if you're the active application, you're bouncing,
游戏正在进行 什么会导致你不再成为活动程序
you're playing your game, what could cause you to stop being active application?
显然 只要用户点了home键 并进入另一个程序
Well, obviously someone could click on the home button and go to another app,
不过还有可能有其它情况
but there's other things too that could happen.
iPhone上可能会有来电
A phone call could come in on your iPhone,
这时任何活动程序都需要停止 UI需要处理来电
now you've stopped being the active app, whatever the UI is for handling a phone call.
哪怕是通知 这很重要
Even notifications, very important,
系统通知也可以出现 让你的程序呈灰色
system notifications can come up and, you know,
并在中间弹出一个警告窗口
they gray out your app, they put an alert view in the middle,
给你某项通知
and some notification happened,
这也会让你的程序停止活动
that could make your app stop being active.
知道程序何时停止活动非常重要
So it's important to know when your app stops being active,
例如Bouncer 它可以暂停游戏
like Bouncer, so Bouncer can pause the game.
我希望将程序的活动性
So I like to think of active, the activeness
对应于程序的暂停/继续
of your application being the pause/resume of your application.
你可以知道这些状态
So you find out about these,
应用程序委托有这些方法
your application delegates have these methods.
applicationDidBecomeActive
Application did become active,
applicationWillResignActive
application will resign active, right?
这是在两种状态间转换
That's going in between the two states,
不过这里还有一个广播站
but there's also a radio station for it.
理解这个很重要 这里还有广播站
And that's important to understand, there's this radio station too,
你可以有视图控制器
and so you can have view controllers
像这个Bouncer的
like this Bouncer guy,
监听广播站 弄清情况并进行暂停
listen to the radio station and find this out and do the pausing.
等下我们就会在demo中这样做
So we're going to do that in the demo in a second.
既然讲到了这里 我就来讲下应用状态的其它内容吧
While I'm here, though, let me talk about some other application state things.
其中之一是后台/前台
One of them is background/foreground,
这同活动/非活动是不同的
which is a different thing than active/not active.
活动是说你在前台 而且你在接收事件
Active means you're in the foreground, and you're receiving events.
当用户换程序时 你不再活动
When someone clicks to go on some other app, you stop being active,
但你还没在后台
but you're not in the background yet.
你可以把后台看成是被搁置了起来
You can think of background as kind of being shelved. You're being put on the shelf.
搁置起来后 你就不再运行
And when you're put on the shelf, you don't run.
在后台运行的情况只有 后台取回
The only time you're ever going to run when you're on the shelf is a background fetch,
几周前我们看到过
which we saw a couple weeks ago,
或者 你是一种特殊应用
or your a special kind of app,
例如VOIP应用 或是位置服务应用
like a VOIP app or a location services app,
这时你就可以在后台
where you're getting locations, then you can come off the shelf
偶尔运行一下 但你是被搁置的
and run for a little bit occasionally, but you're being shelved.
后台就是搁置
So background is shelving.
活动是说 你或许还是用户正在使用的应用程序
Active is just, you might still be the app that the user is using,
但或许有别的东西暂时打断了这个
but something has happened to interrupt that, maybe temporarily.
活动是是否接收事件
So active is whether you're receiving events.
它是暂停/继续
It's kind of a pause/resume.
后台是搁置
Background is shelved.
在被搁置之前
So before you get shelved,
你显然希望你的世界打理干净了
you want to definitely make sure your world's cleaned up
一切都处在良好状态 因为
and everything is a nice state, because one thing,
搁置的东西有可能被清理 你会被丢掉
the shelf can sometimes be cleaned off and you're thrown out.
如果内存出现问题这些
If memory became a problem or something
你可能完全无法再运行
like that you could just completely never run again.
被放入后台时 你需要知道这些
So when you get put in the background, you want to know about that maybe.
你还需要在回前台的时候弄清
But you find out when you come back in the foreground, too.
这样你就可以撤销
So, you know, then you can undo.
通常在前台 你会撤销你在后台做的
Usually in the foreground one, you undo what you did in the background one.
还有一些应用程序委托项目也很有趣
There are some other application delegate items of interest
你们可以到说明文档中查一下
that you can look up in the documentation.
一个是本地通知
One is local notifications.
本地通知是进行计划安排
Local notifications are a way for you to schedule
让程序中某个东西在特定时间日期发生
something to happen in your app at a certain date and time,
这个发生时 如果你的程序没在运行
and when that happens, if your application is not running,
程序就可以启动来处理它
you can be launched to handle it.
这是一种让程序在特定时间运行的方式
So it's a way to kind of make sure your app runs at a certain time.
例如日历程序 它就是这样提醒你特定事件
So like the calendar app, this is how it would make sure
例如你要在什么时候去上课 或是别的什么
that you got reminded that you're supposed to go to class or whatever, even
有时日历程序甚至没在运行
if the calendar app is not even running.
本地通知你们可以看看
So local notification is something to look at.
状态恢复 如果你被搁置了
State restoration, if you got put on the shelf,
然后被关闭 用户重新运行你
and then you got killed, and the user ran you again,
你不希望你的UI以最初UI的形式出现
you don't want your UI to come up like in some base start UI,
你希望UI能呈现出搁置时的状态
you still want to come back to where it was when you got put on the shelf.
状态恢复能够帮你跟踪之前的UI状态
So state restoration is a formalism where you keep track
你被搁置 然后被关闭
of where your UI is, so when you get put on the shelf,
之后重启时 你就能回到这种状态
if you get killed and have to come back, you can restore your state to where it was.
数据保护很有趣
Data protection is an interesting one.
这是一种保护文件的方式
There are ways to protect files that say
如果设备被锁 在锁屏条件下
if this device is locked, in other words, at the lock screen,
那么你就不能访问这个文件
then you can't access this file.
如果没锁 你就能访问
But if it's unlocked, then you can.
这是一种特殊的保护
So it's kind of a special kind of protection.
你可以了解到何时有锁 何时没锁
You can find out about changes in that, i.e., when the thing is locked and unlocked,
也有方法能够让你知道当前有没有锁
and also there's method in there for finding out currently is it locked or not.
然后还有Open URL
Then there's open URL.
Open URL很酷 你可以到Xcode
Open URL is kind of a cool thing, you can go into X code
在项目设置中找到info选项卡
if you go to the info tab there in project settings.
在这里定义一个URL 不是http:什么什么
You can define a URL, like not http colon something
而是Photomania:什么什么这些
but like PhotoMania colon something, for example,
假设Photomania想要做这个
if PhotoMania wanted to do it.
如果其他人
And then if other people
在其它程序中说
in other apps say
open URL Photomania://
open URL PhotoMania colon slash slash,
什么什么什么 问号 这个 那个
something something something, question mark, this, that,
这样的完整URL
all the full URL things you can do in the world of URLs,
那么Photomania就会被启动 处理那个URL
then PhotoMania would get launched to go handle that URL.
这里会有应用程序委托方法被调用 处理这个URL
And there will be application delegate method called, handle this URL.
这是应用程序委托中值得看看的另外一个东西
So that's another thing to look at in application delegate.
好 这方面就这些了
Okay. So. That's the end, that's all I wanted to cover on that.
下面回到Bouncer
But now, let's go back to Bouncer,
演示这个的使用
and show using this.
我打算在停止活动时暂停
I'm going to pause when I get, stop being active, and I'm going
重新活动时 我将继续
to un-pause when I go back to being active.
做法很简单
And the way I'm going to do that, very simple,
NSNotificationCenter
NS notification center,
defaultCenter
default center,
addObserverForName
add observer for name,
我要的是UIApplicationWillResignActive
and the one I want is UIApplicationWillResignActive.
这会在应用程序退出活动时发生
So that happens when I'm going to resign being the active application.
object:Nil 我不在乎这来自于谁
And object nil, I don't really care who-- whoops! Who this comes from.
反正它会来自某个应用程序对象
It's going to come from the application, whatever, application object.
queue 可以在我调用这个的队列上
Queue, fine to do it on this queue that I'm calling this from.
然后这里是我要使用的block
And then, here's the block I want to do,
在我的程序中这很简单 self pauseGame
in my app, really simple, self, pause, game.
我将让程序不再活动 这就需要暂停
I'm going to resign being the active application, so I'm going to pause.
回到这里来做相同的事情
And similarly, can do the same thing when I come back,
不过这里是UIApplicationDidBecomeActive
but here it's UIApplicationDidBecomeActive,
而这里我想要继续
and here I want to resume.
看看这能否正常工作
So let's see if this works.
好 开始游戏
Alright, so let's get this doing something
我们来得点分数 有了
so we can see some points being scored, there we go.
现在我们得到了一些分数 80 90 100 110
Okay so we've got some points, we're about 80, 90, 100, 110,
暂停后 我还是会在110多分 看 再次暂停
okay so if I pause, I'll still be at 110-ish, see, pause again.
分数还是原来的分数 之后会快速降低
Okay, my score is saying the same score, down now pretty fast
因为我没有撞击黑色方块 再让它运动起来
because I'm not hitting that black block, let's get him going again.
分数重新加起 下面再去另一个app
Get the score back up, okay now I'm going to go to another app.
105 113 我们去另一个app
105, 113, so let's go to another app.
我可以进设置 我的app现在应该暂停了
Okay, maybe settings or something like that, and my app right now is paused, I hope.
回来看看Bouncer是不是和原来一样
So let's go back and hopefully Bouncer will be
差不多 还是100左右
about where it was, and it is, it was at about 100.
实际上 我们可以回头看看
Now, in fact, if we go away and come back, if you first look,
回来时它显示了一下暂停 因为这里确实暂停了
you'll see it shows paused for a second because it was paused.
你们还可以看到 这里是71 70 69 68 67
Also, though, you'll notice that see this is 71, 70, 69, 68, 67.
等我回来时 它不是66 而是更少一些 这里是65
But now when I come back it's not going to be at 66, it's farther along, see 65.
为什么呢
Why is that?
这是因为它还运行了几秒
Well that is because it does get to run for a few seconds.
我点到别的app时
When I click to go to another app,
这个app还会保持活动几秒钟
I stay the active app for a few seconds,
运行一下后才不是活动app
and it gets to run a little bit, and now I'm not the active app,
我暂停 然后回来
so I pause, and then we come back.
这里有点时间差 我只是想让你们知道一下
So there is a short amount of time there, just so you know there's that window.
我们想要暂停和继续的最后一个地方是这里
The last place that we want to pause and resume is here.
这是viewDidAppear
Here's viewDidAppear,
这里已经是继续了 之前是开始
we're already resuming here because we used to be starting
现在我们改为了继续
and then we changed it to resume.
显然 在viewWillDisappear中 我们希望暂停游戏
Obviously in view will disappear, we want to self pause game.
这是我们点到标签栏中
That's again if we're in the tab bar,
点另一个选项卡时的情况 我们希望暂停 然后回来
click on another tab, we want to pause and come back.
好 我还没有讲动作表单
Okay, so I didn't get to do action sheet.
我会发布动作表单的代码
I will post the code for the action sheet thing.
对于动作表单
All I was going to do in the action sheet
我只是在Photomania中添加了一个按钮
is just add another button in PhotoMania
来进行照片选择 叫作照片滤镜
to do the little photo choosing, called filter photo,
它会给你一个动作表单
and it was going to put up an action sheet,
你可以选一个滤镜 例如黑色
and you could pick a photo like, or a filter, like I had noir,
铬黄 模糊
and chrome, and blur,
你选一个 然后应用滤镜
you pick one of those, and it would apply the filter to it,
这就是动作表单的作用
and that's all we were doing on the action sheet.
它会告诉你如何弹出动作表单
But it shows you how to put up an action sheet,
加载一些东西 然后对它作出反应
load it up with some things, and respond to it.
我今天会发布代码 你们会看到具体怎么做
So I'll just post that code today and you'll get to see that.
好 就这些了
Okay, that is it.
下周是感恩节 我们一周半以后再见
Uh, Thanksgiving next week so I will not see you for a week and a half.
期末项目请不要耽搁
Don't procrastinate on your final projects everybody.
请正常推进 有问题的可以来问我
Get them going and if you have any questions I'll be here.
谢谢
Thank you.
更多内容 请访问我校官网stanford.edu
> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.